Pablo Solis Herrera

Industrial Engineer / MSc Big Data & Data Science (Ongoing)

Industrial engineer with 5 years of experience, as data analyst, controlling and manager positions. The most of my experience have been focused to solve problems through data and detecting the problems through **business intelligence models using Qlikview and Power Bl.**

I have a background in controlling including cost control, KPI, project control, data science & business intelligence tools as Qlikview and Power Bi.

I am an honest, reliable, quick learner, proactive and hardworking person who likes to challenge myself both personally and professionally. I always look for ways to add value to my organization.

Work History

2019-12

Senior Data Analyst - First Line Engineer

- present

ATMS Technology, Reñaca, Chile

ATMS is a company based in England with a data analysis office in Chile. We work in coordination with different members of the company and clients, who are in different parts of the world.

- -I work mainly in English creating different solutions and analysis, for different clients around the world.
- -Development of different reports and analisys.
- -Solve customer problems related to the WebTrack system that manages data, used for different analyzes.

2018-11 - 2019-06

Team Leader & Project manager (BI project)

Lime, Sydney, Australia

My role in the company has been from Operation Specialist, Team Leader & Data project manager

Key Responsibilities

- · In charge of the development of different business intelligence models through Power BI.
- Responsible to analyze information from the system and from there create a action plan to be assigned to the team I was in charge.

2018-02 - 2018-10

Stock Manager

Mad Monkey Holding, Cairns, Australia

Mad Monkey has 4 hostels in Cairns. I was the stock manager, who aims to get different ways to reduce cost whilst keeping the same service quality. Key Responsibilities

- Design a **Qlikview** model to the stock planning, cost control and create information to negotiate prices with the providers.
- Detect changes in the services, using one of the hostels to detect if we could go down in some cost and how much we could save.

2014-07 - 2016-10

Controlling at IT Operation area

CSAV- Chile (Merger process between CSAV and Hapag Lloyd), Valparaiso, Chile

I was responsible for the cost control, KPI, management reports, control and planning of different projects

Key Responsibilities



Personal Info

Email

pablo.solis.herrera@gmail.com

Phone

+56934333543

Address

Chile

Citizenship

Chilean

Skills

Leadership	***
Teamwork	***
Problem solving	***

Project management

Creativity and innovation

Controlling

Tableau

Business intelligence/analytics



Software

Microsoft power bi

Microsoft office

Qlikview

Sql

Python

Google analytics

- Costs Control & Detect different opportunities to optimize resources.
- \cdot KPIs Control: Generating models in ${\bf QlikView}$ to analyze and identify service improvements
- PMO: Controlling and planning different initiatives
- Process Management: Detecting improvements in different services
- · Billing control according to agreements with suppliers

2013-10 - 2014-07

Controlling at Quality Assurance Management area

SOPROLE (Fonterra Chile), Santiago, Chile

I was responsible for the cost and KPI control, management reports, detecting and analyzing any problems within the ambit of my responsibility and finding an appropriate solution.

Key Responsibilities

- Preparation of the weekly cost control report, Quality Control Management Report, Monthly Quality Control Management Report
- · KPI Management
- Budget and CAPEX process coordinator.

Education

2006-03

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Valparaíso, Valparaíso

- 2012-12

Bachelor Degree, Industrial Engineering

2021-03

Barcelona University

- present

Master degree, Big Data & Data Science

Projects

2020-06

Verdiatek

- present

Founder

Due to the pandemic, we created a sanitizing structure to esterilice any object without the need to use chemicals, only using UVC light. We created, produce and sold this product to contribute with the pandemic

Certificates

Microsoft Certified: Data Analyst Associate with Power BI

Link: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-48ed81f4-c5c1-4877-8e75-7f1441a7ba55/

Languages

English skills



Hobby

Running, swimming & trading